Guide to the Leon Kolb collection of Portraits: engravings, etchings, mezzotinits, lithographs, and acquatints, M0871
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 1. Accn 1972-002, 12.0 Linear feet 1647 items (prints)
  - 0944. Mersenne, Mann, 1588-1648 (Flat-box 8, Folder 2)
    Mann Mersenne/de l’ordre des pares Mlnimes./C1.Duflos Sculp. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 24.6 x 18.6 cm. Singer No. 20575/63713.
  - 0945. Metastasio, Pietro Antonio Domenico Buonaventura, 1698-1782 (Flat-box 8, Folder 2)
    Metastasio./Engraved by R.Page for the Encyclopoedia Londinensis. 1816. Bust in oval looking slightly right. Stipple-engraving. 16.2 x 11.3 cm.
  - 0946. Mettennich, Clemens Wenzel Nepomuk Lothar, prince of, 1773-1859 (Flat-box 8, Folder 2)
    Metternich./F.Lieder gez. Kynil und Franz StUber gest. in Stahl. Wien 1S3O./Inst.Bibl. excudit. Meyers Cony. Lex. No.19. Bust in oblong looking left. Steel-engraving. 24.6 x 16.3 cm. No. 19 from unidentified edition of Mayer’s Lexikon.
  - 0947. Meulen, Pieter van der, 1640-1690 (Flat-box 8, Folder 2)
    Peter Vandder Meulen./A.Bannerman sculp. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 18.4 x 14.0 cm.
  - 0948. May, Adolf von, ca 1648 (Flat-box 8, Folder 2)
    Adolf de Mey./Celsissimae Pnimcipis. Dominae /uneliae/Elisabethae Hasso Landgraviae e Regen/tis Protnibunus legionis pedestnis, et Norim/bergam ad Tractatus pacis executorios Legatus./Anselmus van Hulle pinxit. Petrus de Jode sculpsit. Accessit Privilegium Caesa- reum cum pnivilegio Regum at Holl.ordi. Bust looking left in oval lettered: "Deo dante nil valet invidia.” Engraving. 30.7 x 20.5 cm. Sineer No. 20672/63912. No. 94 from unidentified edition of: Hulle, A.van, Pacificatores orbis Christiani.
  - 0949. Meyer zum Hasen, Jakob, 1480-1531 (Flat-box 8, Folder 2)
    Jacobus Meierus/Reip: Basil: quondam consul prudentiss:/Pietatis sanae Cultor ac Promoter primanius/Natus Basil: 1470. ob.l541./Joh.Holbein pinxit annum agans XVIII. ext. Basil: in Museo Feschiano./Joh.Holbein pimx. B.HUbnen scuip. 1790. Half-portrait in oblong looking right. Engraving. 30.2 x 21.5 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0950. Mierevelt, Michiel Jansz, 1567-1641 (Flat-box 8, Folder 2)
    Michael Mirevelt./Iconum Pictor in Hollandia./Ant.van Dyck pinxit. Wilhelm lac. Deiphins sculpsit. Cum pnivilegio. Half-portrait in oblong looking night. Engraving. 26.2 x 19.4 cm. Singer No. 20810/64177. Dutuit No. 32.5e. Mauquoy-H. No. 26. VIII. From: Icono~raphy of Vandyke.
  - 0951. Mieris, Frans van, 1689-1763 (Flat-box 8, Folder 3)
    Francois Miens. Bust in baroque oval, looking right. Engraving. 11.7 x 8.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0952. Mieris, Frans van, 1689-1763 (Flat-box 8, Folder 3)
    Fran.s Mieris./From a Drawing in the Collection of the Earl of Bute./Mienis del.t Baillia s. Pub. January. 1777. Half-portrait in oblong looking left. Lithograph. 29.4 x 22.3 cm.
  - 0953. Mignard, Pierre [Mignard le Romain], 1612-1695 (Flat-box 8, Folder 3)
    Pierre Mignand/Premlen Peintre du Roy/Seipse Pinxit. Edelinck Sculp. C.P.R. Bust in oval looking left. Engraving. 25.3 x 18.6 cm. Singer No. 20820/64223.
  - 0954. Mijtens, Daniel, ?-1658 (Flat-box 8, Folder 3)
    Daniel Mytens./Ant.van Dyck pinx. A.Bannerman scuip. Bust in oblong looking right. Engraving. 18.5 x 14.6 cm. From: Walpole, H. Earl of Orfond, Anecdotes of Painting, London, 1782.
  - 0955. Mijtens, Daniel, ?- 1658 (Flat-box 8, Folder 3)
    Coyp 2.
  - 0956. Mijtens, Daniel, ?-1658 (Flat-box 8, Folder 3)
    Daniel Mytens/Hollandus Pictor Humanarum Figurarum/Ant.van Dyck pinxit. Paul du Pont sculp. Cum pnivilegio. Half-portrait in oblong looking left. Engraving. 25.2 x 18.4 cm. Singer No. 21751/66625. Dutuit No. 62. Mauquoy-R. No. 56.IX. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 0957. Mildert, Jan van, ?-1638 (Flat-box 8, Folder 3)
    Joannes van Nildert/Statuarius Antvarpiae. Natione Germanus./Ant.van Dyck pinxit. Vorsterman sculp./Cun pnivilegio. Half-portrait in oblong looking night. Etching. 23.9 x 15.7 cm. Singer No. 20836/64264. Dutuit No. 94.5a. Mauquoy-H.No. 87.IX. From: Icono~raphy of Vandyke.
  - 0958. Miller, Johann Martin, 1750-1814 (Flat-box 8, Folder 3)
    Johann Martin Miller. /Prediger am MUnster und Professor/am Cymnasio zu Ulm./gab. d.3 Dezember 1750. J.E.Haid Sc. Bust in circle looking left. Mezzotint. 21.8 x 14.6 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0959. Miller, Johannes, 1705-? (Flat-box 8, Folder 3)
    Joannes Petrus Miller A.M./Gymnasii Ulmani Patrii Rector Gravissimus./Auctonum classicorum latinorum/Editon Lllustris./Natus A.C. 1705./Nicolaus Kleemann pinxit 1777. J.E.Haid Sc. A.V.l777. Bust in oval looking right. Mezzotint. 22.0 x 14.0 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0960. Milton, John, 1608-1674 (Flat-box 8, Folder 3)
    John Milton Aetat 62/ Engraved by Holl./London: Published Nov. 23d. 1799. by T. Heptins and Holborn. Bust in oval looking slightly right. Stipple-engraving. 19.7 x 14.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0961. Minns, Sir Christopher, ?-1666 (Flat-box 8, Folder 4)
    Sir Christopher Minns./Admiral/Obit 1666./Engraved from a drawing by Bullfinch after the original picture when/in the possession of his son Capt.n Minns./London Published-by S.Woodburn 1813./R.Dunkarton sculpsit. Bust in oval looking left. Mezzotint. 29.1 x 20.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0962. Mirabel, Antonio de Zuniga y Davila, ?-1658 (Flat-box 8, Folder 4)
    Don: Antonius De Zuniga Et Davila, Manchio/Mirabellae, Comes Branteviliae, Ordinis Calatren.is/Philip.o IV.Hispan.um Regia Supremis Consilys Status Etc./Antonius van Dyck pinxit. Coenradus Waumans sculpsit. Jacobus de Man excudit. Half-portrait in oblong looking left. Engraving. 27.1 x 19.5 cm. Singer No. 20.907/64445. Dutuit No. l54.3e. Mauquoy-H. No. 150.111. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 0963. Mittenmaien, Carl J.Anton, 1787-1867 (Flat-box 8, Folder 4)
    Mit termaier. /C.Barth Sc. Bust in oblong looking left. Stipple-engraving. 18.0 x 10.8 cm.
  - 0964. Mole de Lassy Edouard, 1540-1614 (Flat-box 8, Folder 4)
    Edouard Mole Conseil du Roy en ses Consails at President au Pariernent./Dedie a Messire Mathieu Mole./Chevalien Premier President au Parlernent/et Garde des Sceaux de France./Son tres humble serviteur R.Nanteuil/avec privilege. Bust in lettered oval looking right. Engraving. 29.2 x 20.4 cm. Singer No. 21047/65756. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0965. Moliere, Jean Baptiste Poquelin, 1622-1673 (Flat-box 8, Folder 4)
    Molière./Chapman Sculpsit./Engraved for the Encyclopoedia Londinensis. May 1817. Bust in oval looking slightly right. Four masks in oblong below. Stipple-engraving. 16.2 x 11.3 cm.
  - 0966. Moliere, Jean Baptiste Poquelin, 1622-1673 (Flat-box 8, Folder 4)
    Molière./Peintura appartenant a Mgr. le due d’Aumale./A.Gilbert del. Exposition Univenselle./Gazette des Beaux Arts./Imp. A.Quantin Paris. Bust in oval looking right. Etching. 17.8 x 14.8 cm.
  - 0967. Molino, Francesco, 99th Doge of Venice, ?-1655 (Flat-box 8, Folder 4)
    Serenissimus Venetae Reip. Ch.Princeps/Franciscus Molinus./R.Custodis. S.l646. Knee-piece in oblong looking right. Engraving. 19.9 x 13.4 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Singer No. 21063/64800.
  - 0968. Momper, Josse de, 1564-1635 (Flat-box 8, Folder 4)
    ludocus de Momper/Pictor Montium Antverpiae./Ant.van Dyck pinxit. Voesterman sculp. Cum privilegio. Half-portrait in oblong looking right. Etching. 23.1 x 15.5 cm. Singer No. 21100/64893. Dutuit No. Not. No 7. A late ed. Mauquoy-H. No. Not. No 7. A later ed. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 0969. Momper, Josse de, 1564-1635. (Flat-box 8, Folder 4)
    Josse Momper. Bust in baroque oval looking left. Engraving. 11.7 x 8.6 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0970. Monamy, Peter, 1670?-1749 (Flat-box 8, Folder 4)
    P.Monainy. /J.Bretherton f. Half-portrait in oblong looking left. Stipple-engraving. 17.3 x 13.0 cm.
  - 0971. Moncada de Aytona Francisco de, historian, Spanish, 1586-1635 (Flat-box 8, Folder 5)
    Exellentiss Dominus D.Franciscus de Moncada/Marchio Aytonae Regij exercitus in Belgi cam Praefectus./Petr de lode excud. Ant.van Dyck pinxit. Bust in oval looking left. Engraving. 14.4 x 10.4 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Singer No. 21103/64908.
  - 0972. Moncada, de Aytona, francisco de, 1586-1635 (Flat-box 8, Folder 5)
    Excell.mus D.Franciscus de Moncada, Marchio Aytonae, Comes Ossonae, Vice-/Comes Cabrerae at Baas, Magnus. Senescalcus Regni Arragoniae, Philippo IV./Hispaniar. Ind~ arumq .Regi A Consiliis Status, Eiusdemq Legatus Extraordin, Et.'/Supremus Militae. fern Maniq In Belgio Praefectus./D.A.Van Dyck Eques Pimxit. Voesterman sculpsit. Half-portrait in oblong looking right. Engraving. 26.3 x 17.8 cm, Singer No. 21103/64905. Dutuit No. 1l9.6e. Mauquoy-H. No. 1l7.VIII. From: Iconography of Vamdyke.
  - 0973. Monck [Monk], Nicolas, 1610-1661 (Flat-box 8, Folder 5)
    Clergy, English. Nicholas Monk, Bishop of Hereford./Obit. 1661./From a drawing in pencil by/Asnld Loggan/London Published by S.Woodburn. 18l1./D.Loggan del’t. R.Dunkanton sc.t. Bust in oblong looking right. Mezzotint. 15.7 x 10.8 cm.
  - 0974. Monmouth and Buccleugh, James Scott, duke of, 1649-1685 (Flat-box 8, Folder 5)
    Le Duo de Monmouth. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 27.5 x 19.3 ens.
  - 0975. Monmouth and Buccleugh, James Scott, duke of, 1649-1685 (Flat-box 8, Folder 5)
    Jacques Scot./Duc de/Monmouth/Fils naturel/de Charles II. Roy/d’Angletenre/Van can Werff pinxit. E.Desnochers sculpsit. Bust in circle looking night. Engraving. 30.7 x 18.0 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0976. Momnouth and Bucclaugh, James Scott, duke of, 1649-1685 (Flat-box 8, Folder 5)
    James Scot, Duke of Monmoth/From the original of Rilly in the Collection of/ELla Grate The Duke of Buccleuch./Dnawn by Wm.Hiltom R.A. & Engraved (with Permission) by H.] Fry.( London, Published Decn.l.1819. Knee-piece in oblong looking night. Stipple-engraving. 36.4 x 25.8 cm. Plate-mark partly trimmed off
  - 0977. Monnoyer, Jean Baptiste, 1634-1699 (Flat-box 8, Folder 5)
    John Baptist Monoyer./G.Knellen pinx. T.Chambars sculp. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 17.1 x 13.0 cm.
  - 0978. Monstrelet, Enguenrand de, ca 1450 (Flat-box 8, Folder 5)
    Enguerrand de Monstrelet. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 18.3 x 13.2 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0979. Montaigne, Michel Eyquen de, 1533-1592 (Flat-box 8, Folder 5)
    Montaigne, Grave sun acier par Hopwood. Bust in oblong looking right. Steel-engraving. 12.4 x 8.3 cm.
  - 0980. Montaigne, Michel Eyquem de, 1533-1592 (Flat-box 8, Folder 5)
    Montaigne./J.Chapman Sculpt./Engnaved for the Encyclopoedia Lomdinensis 1817. Bust in oval looking slightly right. Book, compasses, flowers etc. in oblong belcs Stipple-engraving. 16.2 x 11.3 cm.
  - 0981. Montausier, Charles de Ste Maure, due de, Tutor of the Grand-Dauphin, 1610-1690 (Flat-box 8, Folder 6)
    Charles de Sainte Maure,/Duc de Montausier./Né le 6.octobre 1610. Mont Ia 17.mai 1690. Peint par Ferdinand. Grave par C.S.Gauchen de l’academie des ants de Londres l871~ Bust in oval looking slightly right. Engraving. 13.5 x 8.2 cm.
  - 0982. Montfont, Jan van, 17th cent. (Flat-box 8, Folder 6)
    D.Joannas de Monfort Serenissimorum Archiducum Et Pnincipum Belgii/Albenti at Elisabethae Aularum Pnimanius. Constitutor Et Exornaton, Nec/Non Regis Catholici Mona- tarum Citna Montes. Gonsilianius, Et Magister/ Generalis, Nobiliumq Dominarun Palatii Serenisime Elisabethae Inviolatus Custos/Antonius van Dyck pinxit. Petnus de lode sculpsit.. .axcudit Antverpiae. Knee-piece in oblong looking night. Left index reaching into lettering. Engraving. 26.8 x 20.2 cm. Dutuit No. 14l.4e. Singer No. 21205/65152. Mauquoy-H. No. 139.111. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 0983. Montholon, Nicolas de, 1736-1761 (Flat-box 8, Folder 6)
    Nicolas de Montholon./Né le 6.Xbre 1736./Conseilleur au Panlement de Paris en 1761.1 nommé Premier President du Parlement de Mats/en Xbre 1764 Premier Président du Panlement/ de Rouen en Xbre 1774./C.V.Gochin Eques del. Nicolet sculp. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 22.0 x 16.3 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0984. Montoya, Luis de, 1497-1569 (Flat-box 8, Folder 6)
    Ludovicus de Montoya Ord. Erem./S.Augustini vivum pietalis, Modestiae et/vintutis Simulacrum, Gonscientiae Regis Sebastiani/Praefectus, obyt minaculis clarus./I,Fran in. Bust in Baroque oval, flanked by angels, looking right. Engraving. 13.3 x 9.9 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0985. Montrose, James Graham, let marquess of, 1612-1650 (Flat-box 8, Folder 6)
    James Graham, First Marquis of Montroee./Fnom the original of Vandyke in the collection of/His Grace, The Duke of Montrose/Orawn by Wm.Hilton R.A. & Engraved (with Permission by R. Coopen./London. Published March 1, 1819.by R.Cooper./London. Published March 1.1819. Stipple-engraving. 36.4 x 25.8 cm. Plate-mark partly trimmed off.
  - 0986. Moor, Joos de, ca 1603 (Flat-box 8, Folder 6)
    Joos de Moor./Vice Admiraal van Zealand. /A.Schouman del. naar de Onig. Schildery by den Raadsheer Gaen te Middelbung. J.Houbraken fec./Is.Tinion excud. 1760. Bust in oval looking left, framed by oblong. Engraving. 18.5 x 11.8 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark. Singer No. 21267/65307.
  - 0987. Mondaunt, John, viscount, 1627-1675 (Flat-box 8, Folder 6)
    John Viscount Mordaunt/ob 1675 aet. 48./London Published by S,Woodburn 1814. Dunkar- ton sculp.t. Bust in oblong looking right. Mezzotint. 28.9 x 20.2 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0988. More, Hannah, 1745-1833 (Flat-box 8, Folder 6)
    Hannah More./Heath sculp.t. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 18.7 x 14.5 cm.
  - 0989. More, Sir John, 1453?-1530? (Flat-box 8, Folder 6)
    Sir John More./Ob. 1533./From the original of Holbein in the Collection of/The Right Honorable The Earl of Penbroke./Engnaved by W.T.Mote. The London Printing and Publishing Company. Half-portrait in oblong looking left, Photo-engraving. 27.2 x 18.3 cm.
  - 0990. More, Sir Thomas, Saint, 1478-1535 (Flat-box 8, Folder 6)
    Sir Thomas More./Ob.1535./ From the Original of Holbein in the Collection of/W.J. Lenthal Esqre,/The London Printing and Publishing Company./Engraved by H.T.Ryall. Seated knee-piece in oblong looking night. Photo-engraving. 27.2 x 18.3 cm.
  - 0991. More, Sir Thomas, Saint, 1478-1535 (Flat-box 8, Folder 7)
    Sn Thomas Mone./Holbein pinxit J.Houbnaken sculps./Ainst.174O. Impensis I.& P.Kmapton, Londini, 1741./In the Possession of Sn Rowland Winn.Bant. Bust in oval looking left; sceptre, book and axe in lower foreground. Engraving. 37.0 x 21.5 cm. Singer No. 21287/65362. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0992. More, Sir Thomas, Saint, 1478-1535 (Flat-box 8, Folder 7)
    Thomas Monus./R.Inventor./FLD Ciantres excudit cum Privilegio. Bust facing viewer in oblong. Etching. 22.5 x 19.0 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark. No. 26 from: Langlois F. Lalivre original de la portraiture, Paris, 1644.
  - 0993. Monice, Sin William, 1602-1676 (Flat-box 8, Folder 7)
    Sn. William Monice./Secretany of State to King Charles 11./In the Collection of Sr. William Monice Bart./J.Houbraken sculps. Mist. 1797./Impensis J.& P. Knapton Londini 1747. Bust in oval looking slightly left surrounded by Baroque composition. Engraving. 37.2 x 23.5 cm, Singer No. 21328/65494. From: Birch, T., The Heads of the Mostt Illustrious Persons of Great Britain, J.Knapton, London, 1747.
  - 0994. Monin, Jean, 1591-1659 (Flat-box 8, Folder 7)
    Jean Monin/Père de L’Onatoira./Jac.Lubin Sculp. Bust in oval looking left. "Iesus Maria” in wreath of thorns in lower center. Engraving. 25.5 x 19.8 cm. Singer No. 21333/65507.
  - 0995. Monland, Sin Samuel, 1625-1695 (Flat-box 8, Folder 7)
    Samuel Monlandius Ser.mi D.ni Protectonis, Ad Regem/Galliae Ducemq, Sabaudiae de Rebus Vallensium/Internantus, et Deinde Extra Ondine Comissanius./P.Lilly pinxit. P. Lombart sculpsit.
  - 0996. Morley, George, bp. of Winchester, 1597-1684 (Flat-box 8, Folder 7)
    George Monely Bishop of Winchester./In the Collection of the Honble Lieutenant General Dormer, at Rousham./P.Lelly Equ. pinxit/G.Ventue Sculp. 1740. Bust in lettered oval facing viewer, surrounded by symbolic Baroque composition. Engraving. 36.0 x 23.6 cm. Singer No. 21352/65674. From: Birch, T., The Heads of the Most Illustrious Persons of Great Britain, J.Knapton, London, 1743.
  - 0997. Mono van Dashoret, Antonis, 1512?-1578? (Flat-box 8, Folder 7)
    Sr.Antonio Mona./T.Chambans sculp. Bust in oblong looking night. Engraving. 17.3 x 13.0 cm.
  - 0998. Morton, James Douglas, 4th earl of, 1530-1581 (Flat-box 8, Folder 7)
    James, Earl of Morton, 1581./In the Possession of the Right Hon: the Earl of Morton./ J.Houbraken sculps. Anst.1740./Impansis I.& P.Knapton. Londini, 1741. Bust in lettered oval looking slightly left surrounded by Baroque composition. Engraving. 37.5 x 23.5 cm. Singer No. 21381/65732. From: Birch, T., Thelleads of theMost Illustrious Perspp~s of Great Britain,J.Knapton, London, 1743.
  - 0999. Morton, Thomas, 1764-1848 (Flat-box 8, Folder 7)
    Morton, the Dramatist./From the picture in the Vernon Galleny./Sir M,A.Sheer P.R.A. painter, T.W.Hunt engraven./Pninted by G.Virtue./London published for the pnopnietons./ Size of the picture...
  - 1000. Motz, Fniednich von, 1775-1830 (Flat-box 8, Folder 7)
    Fr. v. Motz./KUnigh. Preuss. Finanz ministar./Gez.von KnDger. Ms. G.L. No.805. Bust in oblong facing viewer. Stipple-engraving 16.6 x 10.0 cm. Singer No. 21426/65847.
  - 1001. Muller, Peter, 1640-1696 (Flat-box 8, Folder 8)
    Petrus Mlfllerus Ictg. Henedit in Moderwiz et Leithethal, Consiliani, Saxon: in Acad; Jenensi Antecess. Cur provinc. Scabinat, ac Colleg. lunidici Assessor./Philip Kilian sculps. Bust in lettered oval looking slightly night. Engraving. 22.5 x 15.2 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 1002. Munillo, Bantolome Esteban, 1618-1682 (Flat-box 8, Folder 8)
    [Munillo self portrait.] Bust in oblong looking night. Etching. 21.3 x 14.4 cm.
  - 1003. Murillo, Bartolome Esteban, 1618-1682 (Flat-box 8, Folder 8)
    Bart.Murillo seipsun depin gems profiliorum votis ac preci/bus explendis./Munillo pi. G.0. Murray cc. Bust in oval looking right. Etching. 20.7 x 15.0 cm.
  - 1004. Murillo, Bartolome Esteban, 1618-1682 (Flat-box 8, Folder 8)
    Bartolomé Estevan Munillo./H.Adlard sc./Pninted by Wittman, Panis./Vera effigies Bartholomaei Stephani ~ Monillo Maxirni Pictonis/Hispali nati Anno 1618 obijt Ammo 1682 tertia die mensis Apnij is. Bust in oval looking right. Stipple-engraving, 16.5 x 12.0 cm.
  - 1005. Murray, Thomas, 1663-1734 (Flat-box 8, Folder 8)
    Murray. /A.Bamnerman Sculp. Bust in oval looking night. Engraving. 18.5 x 13.9 cm.
  - 1006. Musius, Cornelis, 1503-1572 (Flat-box 8, Folder 8)
    Cornelius Musius. /H.Larmessin scnipsenit. Bust in oblong looking right. Engraving. 17.3 x 13.0 cm.
  - 1007. Myddeltom [Middleton], Sir Hugh, Governor of Denbigh, 1560-1631 (Flat-box 8, Folder 8)
    Sir Hugh Middleton./From the original in Goldsmith’s Hall London.! Drawn by W.Hilton R.A. & Engraved (with Permission) by E.Scniven./London Published Sept.n. 25.1820, by Lackington, Hughes, Harding, Mayor & Jones and Longman, Hurst, Rees, Orme & Brown. Knee-piece in oblong Stipple-engraving. 36.4 x 25.8 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 1008. Mylius in Gnadenfeld, Henmann, 1600?-1657? (Flat-box 8, Folder 8)
    enmann Myllus:/In Gnadenfelt lotus Caesareae at Regiae/Maiestatis Daniae nec non Ilustnissimi Domini/Anthon-Guntheni, Comitis in Oldenburg et/Delmenhorst Domini in Feueren et Kniphausen,/Consilianius Cones Palatinus et Judex Provincialis Knip/hausanus,Ad Tractatus Pacis Westphaliae, et/Gomitia Ratisbonensia LLegatos Ano 1652./Anselmus va Hulle pinxit et Peter de Baillu scuip. Gun privilegio Regum at Hollandiae ordinum. Bust looking left in oval lettered: "Der Herr ist main Gut und main Theil. Ps: XV. Ver. 5.” Engraving. 29.9 x 19.1 cm. Singer No. 21736/66588. No. 103 from unidentified edition of: Hulle, A.van, Pacificatones orbis Chnistiani.
  - 1009. Naglen, Karl Ferdinand, 1770-1846 (Flat-box 8, Folder 8)
    V.Nagler./KUnigl. Pr. General Postmeister und/Gesandten am Bundestage./In Stall gest. von Nordhaim/Stich Druck u.Venlag v.Bibliographischen Institut von Hildburghausen. Bust in oblong looking right. Steel-engraving. 17.5 x 12.3 cm. Singer No. 21779/66683.
  - 1010. Nassau, Johann, Graf von, 1583-1638 (Flat-box 8, Folder 8)
    Excell,mus Domimus. D.Ioannes Comes, Nassoviae.Cattinelliboci Vianden/Diets. Etc. Eques. Aurei Vellenis. S.Ma.Gaes. Maneschallus. Cath.Reg./In Belgio. Equitum. Genera- us. Etc./Paul Pontius sculpsit. Ant. van Dyck pinxit. corn pnivilegio. Half-portrait in oblong looking slightly right. Engraving. 24.2 x 17.6 cm. Dutuit No. 63.5e, Mauquoy-H. No. 57.V. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 1011. Nassau-Katzenellembogan, Wilhelm Ludwig, graf von, 1560-1620 (Flat-box 8, Folder 9)
    Johannes Ludovicus Comes de Nassau, Gatzenellnbogen/Vianden et Dietz etc. Dominus de Beijlstein, Eques/Aurei Vellenis, Sae Gaes.ae Majestis Gonsilianius intirnus,/Camena'~ ranius, atq. ad Tractatus Pads univarsalis/eiusdem Maeist.tis nomine Legatos Plenipoten- tianius/Cum pnivilegio Regum at Hollandiae ordinum. accessit Pnivilegium Caesareum. Anselmus van Hulle pinxit. Petrus de lode sculpsit. Bust looking left in oval lettered: "Dulce at decorum est pro patnia non.” Engraving. 31.1 x 19.8 cm.
  - 1012. Nassau-Katzenellenbogen, Wilhelm, Graf von, 17th cent. (Flat-box 8, Folder 9)
    Johan Willem Fniso,/Prins von Onanje,/Enf-Stadhouder van Fniesland,/Stadhouder van Gnomingen enz. /H. de Zuitar pinx. J.Houbraken fecit. /Is .Tiniom excudit. Half-portrait in oblong looking right. Engraving. 18.3 x 11.5 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 1013. Nassau-Katzenellenbogen, Wilhelm, Graf von, 17th cent. (Flat-box 8, Folder 9)
    Johannes Gulielmus Fniso, per Dei Gratiam/Pninceps Nassavius, Comes Cattimeliboco- rum etc. etc. haereditanius Fnisiae,/Gnoningae, et agronum cincumjacemtium Gubernator/ B.Vaillant del, P.van Gunst sculp. F.Halma excudit. Bust in oval wreath facing viewer. Double quatrain signed "David Hoogstnatanus” under coat of arms. Engraving. 37.7 x 27.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 1014. Nelis, Corneille Fnancois de, bp. of Anvers, cardinal, 1736-? (Flat-box 8, Folder 9)
    Corneille Francois de Nelis/XVIIIe Evéque d’Anvers &a.&a.&a./néle 5 Juin 1736, sacrf Evèque le 5 Join 1785./at racu la m8me Anne aux Etats./Dessiné d’après Nature par A.B. de Quertennont. Grave par E:G:Thelott a Düsseldorf. Bust in oval looking right. Cardinal’s hat under plinth. Engraving. 28.0 x 20.3 cm.
  - 1015. Nerli, Francesco, 17th cent. (Flat-box 8, Folder 9)
    Franciscus Nenlius Comes Valdenii etc./Summi Nantuae Magistratus Praeses,.Ducissae Maniae Viduae Regenti a Consiliis/Intenionibus Serenissimi Ducis Mantuani/ad Fractatus Pacis Universalis/Legatus Plenipotentianius. /accessit Pnivilegium Caesareum. Anselmus van Hulle pinxit. Corn,Galleiunior sculp. 1648. Gum pnivilegio Regum at Hollandiae ordinem. Bust looking left in oval lettered: "Judica me Deus, at discerne Causam meam.’ Engraving. Singer No. 21921/67117. No. 80 from: Hulle, A.van, Celeberniini ad pacificandum Christiani nominis orbem Legati.. .Anvers, 1648.
  - 1016. Nero, Claudius, Caesar Augustus Germanicus Lucius Domitius, 6th emperor of Rome, 37-68 A.D. (Flat-box 8, Folder 9)